# Sabrina Kall

Software Engineer

1-703-420-4664

■ sabrina.ckall@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sabrina-kall

Chicago, IL

#### SUMMARY

Highly skilled software engineer with dual US-Swiss citizenship and experience working with many cultures. Specializes in designing and building highly scalable, asynchronous software for machine learning and the cloud. As a tech lead for one of the world's biggest financial regulation software providers, I led a team in the successful design, implementation and delivery of the company's next-generation AI compliance platform.

Github: https://github.com/sigma-libra

StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/8788182/sigma1510

## EXPERIENCE

Tech Lead 08/2021 - Present

IMTF

- Leads an agile team of developers, data scientists, and testers in the design and development of a machine-learning backed financial regulation platform for realtime screening of banking customer data and transactions. We use Docker, Kubernetes, Kafka and Elasticsearch in a microservice architecture with asynchronous communication to be highly scalable and fault tolerant.
- Serves as an architect for the integration of multiple products company-wide, including sunset legacy systems.
- Maintains, deploys to, and supports test, demo and production environments using automated pipelines for Cloud and playbooks for air-gapped on-premise servers.
- Trains teams to use the SCRUM framework.

**Software Engineer** 08/2020 - 08/2021

ti&m

Coded the backend for a cloud-based e-commerce platform with a microservice architecture, Elasticsearch database and asynchronous Kafka communication, and assisted in the design and supervision of deployments to AWS.

**Security Researcher** 02/2020 - 08/2020

SAP

Designed and implemented a python-based federated learning process to train a machine-learning model in the detection of leaked credentials (passwords, sensitive information, etc...), which became the topic of a paper published at the 7th International Conference on Information Systems Security and Privacy.

Coding Teaching Assistant 09/2018 - 01/2020

Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne [EPFL]

Taught C++ to first year Engineering students.

 Student Researcher
 02/2019 - 06/2019

Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne [EPFL]

Developed algorithms for the discovery of malicious nodes in the context of location-based "trust-but-verify" blockchain architectures, and implemented them in Go in order to benchmark them.

#### **EDUCATION**

Computer Science 2020

Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne (EPFL) - Master

• GPA: 5.5/6

Software Engineering 2018

Vienna University of Technology (TUW) - Bachelor (Erasmus exchange student)

Computer Science 2018

SQL (+ Postgres + MySQL)

Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne (EPFL) - Bachelor

## CERTIFICATES

Professional SCRUM Master I

01/2023 - Present

## SKILLS

Terraform

Architecture Design Jupyter Notebook

API Design (REST, Async)

Database Design

Spark

End-to-End Testing

Hadoop

DevOps

Kafka

Product Integration

Flutter

Machine Learning

React

Kubernetes Angular

Helm MongoDB

Docker DynamoDB

AWS Elasticsearch

Java (+ Spring + Junit)

Kotlin

Git

Go CI/CD Pipelines
C++ JIRA + Confluence

Javascript (+ HTML + CSS) SCRUM

Python (+ Flask + Pandas)

## LANGUAGES

EnglishNativeFrenchNativeGermanNativeSpanishFluent